Hurry!
（兵士）
急げ！
（シャリオス）
なんじゃ そちか
Oh, it's just you.
ひやあああ！
Favaro! Rita!
（カイザル）
ファバロ リタ…
What have you done?!
何てことをしてくれたんだ
（ラヴァレイ）
騎士団の諸君！
Knights!
鍵の娘を取り戻さねば 王都に…
Unless we recover the key girl,
the Royal Capital—nay, the world of man—is doomed!
否 人の世に未来はない！
Secure her at once!
一刻も早く確保せよ
Yes, Sir!
Kaisar.
（ラヴァレイ）
カイザル君
Captain Lavalley...
（カイザル）
ラヴァレイ隊長…
I'm giving you your own squad.
（ラヴァレイ）
君に 一隊 預けよう
即刻
アーミラたちの追尾に向かってくれ
I need you to track down
Amira's group immediately.
なぜ 私のような新参者に？
Me? But I'm still but a newcomer.
（ラヴァレイ）
ゴランが殺された
Gaurin has been killed.
What?!
Shh.
アーミラたちではない
It wasn't Amira's group.
But I cannot leave my post here.
だが 私も今
この場を離れるわけにはいかん
Take this.
君に預ける
ほかの隊より早く見つけ出し
あの子を導いてやってくれ
Find her before the other squads do
and guide her on her way.
これ…
But this is...
頼む
Please.
くわあ！
Oh, right. You can fly!
あれ？　お前 飛べんだっけ？
Sorry. I can't.
ごめん 無理
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
Oh, are you scared?
なんだ？　怖いのか？
Nope!
全然
Yeah, I guess not.
ですよねえ…
Do you think my mother will recognize me?
I need to get out of this forest.
（ファバロ）
何とか
この森から抜け出さないと…
I mean, I've grown so much!
Man. Hanging around this little kid is gonna get me killed.
たく… こいつに つきあってたら
命が いくつあっても足りやしねえ
（ファバロ）ガキンチョが…
（アーミラ）ねえ こんなに！
This much!
（ファバロ）
あ～ 分かる 分かる
Yeah, she'll recognize ya.
But...
（アーミラ）
でも…
（ファバロ）
ハア…
そんなもん 黙って
抱き締めてやりゃあ 一発だろ
Seriously. One hug and she'll know right away.
Hey!
（アーミラ）ねえ
（ファバロ）あん？
Will my mother really recognize me if I hug her?
抱き締めれば
お母さんて分かるの？
Yeah. That's how moms are.
おお 母親ってのは そういうもんだ
アハッ
Like this?!
Wh-Whoa! Watch it! Hey!
（アーミラ）こんな感じ？
（ファバロ）なっ なんだ…
（ファバロ）危(あぶ)ねえって おい！
（アーミラ）ギュー！
Gaurin...
ゴラン… 何という姿に
What a terrible fate to meet.
Wh-What were the guards doing?!
え… 衛兵は何をしておった？
They all had their throats slit.
（ラヴァレイ）
皆 喉を裂かれて…
Is that... hair?
これは… 髪の毛でしょうか？
Hair, you say?!
（シャリオス）
髪の毛だと？
It was her! It must have been her!
あやつだ！　あやつに違いない
That witch wants to kill me!
あの魔女が 余を！
This is nonsense! I have no desire to take Your Majesty's life!
（ジャンヌ）
お戯れを！
私が王のお命を狙っているなど！
S-Silence, witch!
だ… 黙れ 魔女め！
This hair is undeniable proof!
この髪の毛が動かぬ証拠
そのようなもの
誰でも手に入れられましょう！
That could've been obtained from anywhere!
You can't fool me!
貴様の魂胆は分かっておる
You came to kill me in my sleep!
余の寝首をかきにきて
ゴランに見とがめられ…
But Gaurin learned of your plan!
I know nothing of these things!
全く身に覚えのないこと！
You can explain during your inquisition!
申し開きは審問の席で聞こう
I demand to see Lord Michael, my guardian angel!
（ジャンヌ）
それでは 我が守護天使
ミカエル様に お目通りを！
Nonsense!
たわけ！
The three archangels have
already departed for Heaven!
三大天使様は
とうに天界へ出立なされたわ
そんな…
That can't be...
Now that the key girl has been lost,
（シャリオス）
鍵の娘を失った以上
it won't be long until the angels forsake this capital.
いずれ この都は
天使様に見限られることになる
It's all your fault...
何もかも 貴様のせいだ！
You filthy, abominable witch!
この…
汚らわしい魔女め！
What is it?
（ファバロ）
どうした？
まだ いる
There are more.
Huh? Where?!
え？　どこ？
Whoa!
チッ… もう追いつかれたのかよ
They found us already?!
Kaisar!
カイザル！
Favaro! Return Lady Amira to the Royal Capital immediately!
ファバロ
アーミラ嬢を連れて王都に帰れ！
Wh-What's your problem?
（ファバロ）
な… なんだよ
Are you mad we left without tellin' ya?
黙って出ていったから
怒ってんのか？
We had a very good reason...
これには 深～い訳が…
Yes, I bet you did!
ああ そうだろうとも！
カイザル てめえ…
What the hell, Kaisar?!
Just play along, okay?
いいから ここは話を合わせてくれ
Huh?
Fava!
ファバ！
Stay out of this, all of you!
お前たちは手を出すな！
Whoa!
Stop!
（カイザル）
やめろ！
Don't kill him!
殺すんじゃない！
Whoa! Hold on a sec!
ちょ… 待て 待て 待て
Hold on, I said!
待てって言ってんだろ！
Lady Amira...
（カイザル）
アーミラ嬢…
（天使）
がはっ！
（ミカエル）
鍵の娘が王都より失われた！
The key girl has been lost from the Royal Capital!
We'll take over from here!
（ウリエル）
ここは我らが引き継ぐ！
You must return to Heaven quickly and have Gabriel send reinforcements!
（ラファエル）
お前は急ぎ天界に戻り
ガブリエルに増援の旨を伝えよ！
At once!
（アークエンジェル）
ははあ！
（ミカエル）
封印の均衡が著しく崩れている
The seal's imbalance is becoming too great.
Make haste, O maiden!
急ぐのだ 乙女よ
Time is of the essence!
もはや 一刻の猶予もならぬ
Oh, poor little saint.
（マルチネ）
かわいそうな聖女…
（ジャンヌ）
何者だ？
Who's there?
Pitiable maiden, abandoned by the gods...
（マルチネ）
神に見捨てられた哀れな乙女
No, I suppose you're a lamb now.
いや 今は子羊
それとも～
Or perhaps...
I should call you a "witch" instead.
魔女と呼んだほうがいいのかなあ？
Are you the one who slew Gaurin?
（ジャンヌ）
貴様か ゴランを亡き者にしたのは
とんでもな～い
Perish the thought.
As a matter of fact, I've come here to save you.
むしろ 私は あなたを
救済しに来たのですよ
To save me?
救済だと？
（マルチネ）
ん～ そのとおり
Indeed.
The humans have betrayed you.
人間たちに裏切られた あなたを…
Nonsense.
（ジャンヌ）
戯言(たわごと)を
I am a sword and shield of the gods.
私は神の矛であり 神の盾
聖なる騎士として殉じるならば
何の悔いもありはしない
As a holy knight, I'd have no regrets giving my life for my duty.
A holy knight?!
（マルチネ）
聖なる騎士！
What an utter untruth!
それこそが大うそ
偽りなのです
Why, you're nothing of the sort.
Who told you that you're a holy knight?
あなた その話 誰から聞きました？
愛しの守護天使様かしら
Was it your beloved guardian angel, I wonder?
（マルチネ）
真実を知りたくはありませんか？
神が隠す真実を
Wouldn't you like to know the truth—
the one that the gods are hiding?
Drink this and the truth will be yours.
これを飲めば
本当の真実が手に入ります
悪魔の言葉に
耳を貸すつもりはない！
I'll lend no ear to the words of a demon!
（マルチネ）
フ～ンフフ
ど～ぞ ど～ぞ ご自由に
Oh, of course! No pressure at all.
決めるのは あなたです
It's entirely your decision.
ただし
これだけは覚えておいてください
I do have one piece of advice for you, though.
No matter what happens to you,
あなたの身に何が起きようと
don't expect your merciful
guardian angel to come to your aid.
慈悲深い守護天使様は
救いに来てはくださるまい
絶対！　絶対に
Because he won't! He won't!
What's going on?!
（兵士）
どういうことだ？
What is this?!
一体 これは…
（カイザル）おい！
（兵士）撤収！
Hey!
Retreat!
Where are you going?!
（カイザル）
どこへ行く！
Can't you see me?! I'm right here!
分からないのか 私は ここだ！
そんな…
I can't believe this.
That's hired help for ya.
所詮は雇われ　あんなもんさ
What's that?!
（カイザル）
何だ？
What's what?
（ファバロ）
どうした？
ふん…
ハア…
ふん！
ぐうう…
だあ…
Sorry. I can't.
ごめん 無理
マジか…
Seriously?
If you guys can't pull it out, there's no way I'll—
お前らに抜けねえもんが
俺に抜けるわけ…
なんで？
How?
C'mon! Don't be so shocked, you guys!
まあまあ ２人とも驚くな
What?!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What's gotten into you guys?!
ちょいちょいちょい
なんだよ お前ら
どうした…
ゴホッ…
You have my thanks.
（ドラゴン）
やれ ありがたい
You have my thanks.
（ドラゴン）
やれ ありがたい
そのトゲには…
That barb had been bothering me for the last two thousand years.
（ファバロ）
トゲ？
Barb?!
（ドラゴン）
かれこれ二千年も
煩わされておったのでな
Who are you, old man?
ジジイ 誰？
そこは“おじいさん”な
Call him "mister" in this case.
Who are you, mister?
おじいさん 誰なの？
I am...
（ドラゴン）
わしは…
"I am..."?
（３人）
わしは？
What you just pulled free is...
（ドラゴン）
おぬしが抜いてくれた それは…
What, no introduction?!
名乗んねえのかよ おい！
It is a barb of Bahamut.
（ドラゴン）
それはバハムートのトゲだ
Barb...
トゲ…
The barb you so kindly removed...
（ドラゴン）
おぬしが抜いてくれた
そのトゲには
It seems it was fated to guide you to this place.
どうやら この地へいざなう因果が
あったようじゃな
Bahamut...
（ファバロ）
バハムート…
（ドラゴン）
バハムート
Bahamut.
It has appeared many times before.
あやつは今まで 幾たびも現れ
その度に
世界に破滅をもたらせてきた
Each time, it brought about the world's ruin.
It last appeared around two thousand years ago.
最後に あやつが現れたのは
およそ二千年前
In what could only be called a miracle,
あのときは奇跡的に
神と悪魔が手を結び
the gods and demons managed to unite and seal Bahamut away.
バハムートを封印することができた
そいつが わしの足に刺さったのも
そのときよ
That's when this barb became lodged in my foot.
位相の異なる空間さえ貫くとは
さすがバハムートといったところか
Tearing into a separate plane of existence like that...
Bahamut is truly marvelous.
Much time has passed since then.
あれから長い時が流れた
しかし 今 また
But Bahamut is now on the verge of breaking free once more...
バハムートの封印が
解かれようとしておる
by way of this young girl.
そこの娘ごによってな
You know of Lady Amira?!
（カイザル）
あなたは アーミラ嬢のことを…
I do.
（ドラゴン）
知っておるよ
わしは永劫(えいごう)の観察者だからな
I am an eternal observer, after all.
This girl is the seal's key.
その娘は“封印の鍵”
（ドラゴン）
鍵が封印とひとつとなり
バハムートが目覚めれば
Should the key and the seal be brought together, Bahamut will awaken and destroy the world.
世界は破滅する
Just as it has countless times before.
これまで
幾たびも繰り返されてきたように…
We won't let that happen!
そんなことはさせない！
The gods and demons are already amassing their forces, however.
（ドラゴン）
だが 既に神と悪魔の軍勢は
集結を始めておる
The key girl is no longer under our control.
（ガブリエル）
鍵の娘が
我らの手元より失せました
If the demons obtain her, they will
undoubtedly converge on the holy land of Abos.
悪魔の手に渡れば
必ずや
聖地エイボスに攻め寄せるでしょう
O warriors of light!
光の戦士たちよ
Gather before my sword and make ready for battle!
我が剣の下に集い
戦いに備えるのです！
The key girl has left the city!
（ベルゼビュート）
鍵の娘が都をたった！
They're plotting to take the holy land for themselves and revive Bahamut!
ヤツらは聖地を占拠し
バハムートを
復活させようとしている
My fallen brothers of darkness!
闇に堕(お)とされし兄弟たちよ
Take up your swords!
剣を取れ！
What are you scheming, Beelzebub?
（ルシフェル）
何を たくらんでいる？
ベルゼビュート
Now is the time to annihilate the gods' forces!
（ベルゼビュート）
今こそ
神の軍勢を討ち滅ぼすときぞ！
Y-You don't mean...
ま… まさか
Whoa, now.
All these jokes are only funny for so long.
んな冗談
いちいち真に受けてらんねえって
Destruction is your fate. Fate cannot be changed.
（ドラゴン）
破滅は運命だ
運命は変えられん
What's wrong, Favaro?
どうした？　ファバロ
It's nothing.
何でもない…
（アーミラ）
私がいたら
世界がなくなっちゃうの？
The world's going to disappear because of me?
Everyone's going to die?!
みんな 死んじゃうの？
（ドラゴン）
そうだ
Yes.
Even my mother?
お母さんも？
（ドラゴン）
そうなるな
So it would stand to reason.
（ドラゴン）
されど お前たちが
ここに迷い込んだのも また運命
But it was also fate that you stumbled into this place.
There may be one way to prevent destruction.
破滅を防ぐすべが
１つだけあるやもしれん
Really?!
ホント？
By living in this separate plane of existence...
（ドラゴン）
閉ざされた この位相の地で
永遠に暮らすことだ
Forever.
ここで… 暮らす？
Live... here?
そうすれば お母さんは？
If I do, what about my mother?
Will I get to see her?
お母さんには？
うわあああん！
It's gone.
（ファバロ）
消えた？
アーミラ…
Amira?
Screw this!
（ファバロ）
ざっけんじゃねえぞ
To hell...
何が…
To hell with fate!
何が運命だ！
（カイザル）
ファバロ？
Favaro?
You're gonna give up after all this?!
ここまで来て 諦めんのか？
You're so close to seeing your mom again!
あと ひと息で 母ちゃんに会える
ってとこじゃねえか
でも…
But if I don't stay here, she'll die.
私がいたら
お母さん 死んじゃうって
（ファバロ）
変えちまえ！　そんな運命
Then change that crappy fate!
Listen up, old man! I've got one thing to say to you!
いいか ジジイ！
１つ忠告しといてやる
We can change fate! As much as we want, however we want!
運命なんざなあ
いくらでも変えられるんだよ
自分の手で！
変えられるの？
We can change it?
Yeah, and we're going to!
（ファバロ）
ああ 変えてやる
Screw this "destruction is our only fate" crap!
破滅しかねえ運命なんか
クソ食らえだ
ハッ 親父(おやじ)が よく言ってたぜ
It's just like my old man used to say!
（バロッサ）
ファバロ
Favaro, which way is the wind blowing?
風は どっちに吹いている？
To tomorrow!
明日だってなあ！
My word!
（ドラゴン）
これは…
あ… あれ？
Huh? What?
Fava!
（アーミラ）
ファバ！
ファバロ… お前の言うとおりだ
Favaro...
You're right! I have nothing more to add!
返す言葉もない
Color me surprised!
これは 一本取られたわい
ファバ すごい！
Amazing, Fava!
Hold on. Is this seriously happening?
（ファバロ）
ちょちょちょ この状況… マジか
I understand. Now, go forth.
（ドラゴン）
よく分かった
さあ 行くがよい
（アーミラ）
いいの？
Are you sure?
（ドラゴン）
わしにできるのは見ることだけだ
All I can do is watch.
I cannot stop you.
留(と)めることはできんよ
I will give the barb of Bahamut to you.
バハムートのトゲは
おぬしにやろう
It's possible it might be able to tear through fate, too.
それがあれば
運命も切り開けるやもしれぬ
ありがたく頂戴しとくよ
I gratefully accept it!
いろいろ ありがとう おじいさん
Thanks for everything, mister!
世話になった 翁(おきな)よ
Thank you, venerable one.
（ドラゴン）
騎士よ
Hear me, knight.
Huh?
（民衆）
なぜ ジャンヌ様が…
ジャンヌ様が火あぶり？
Saint Jeanne is being burned at the stake?!
そんなバカな！
That's crazy!
Saint Jeanne can't possibly be a traitor!
ジャンヌ様が
謀反人でなんかあるものか！
Hey, you! Do you dare oppose the king's decree?!
（衛兵）
おい 貴様！
王の決定に逆らうのか？
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
王よ どうか ご慈悲を
Please show mercy, Your Majesty!
Saint Jeanne would never
harbor rebellious sentiments—
聖女ジャンヌに謀反の心などは
決して…
（シャリオス）
黙れ ラヴァレイ！
Silence, Lavalley!
ジャンヌをたたえる者は
皆 逆賊だ！
Everyone who praises Jeanne is a traitor!
Seize every last one!
残らず ひっ捕らえよ！
Kill them if need be!
殺してもかまわぬ！
Bingo.
（リタ）
ビンゴ
Fungus, foxglove, and mandragora root...
ファンガスにジキタリス
マンドラゴラの根
Cockatrice gizzard and basilisk heart...
コカトリスの砂肝に
バジリスクの心臓…
These are some pretty dodgy items for a castle to have on hand.
お城の備品にしては
随分と物騒なものばかりね
Leftovers of a magic ritual?
魔法儀式の跡？
But this enchantment is...
でも こんな術式って…
（マルチネ）
探し物かな？
Looking for something...
Miss?
お嬢さん
ここが
お母さんのいる場所…
This is where my mother is.
Prudisia.
（カイザル）
ブロドシア
Prudisia
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
What's wrong, Favaro? Are you afraid?
どうした ファバロ 怖いのか？
Don't worry! I'm strong!
（アーミラ）
大丈夫！　私 強いから
Yes, that's right.
（カイザル）
そうだったな
Hear me, knight.
（ドラゴン）
騎士よ 心せよ
Be aware.
As long as the girl is a vessel for the key,
あの娘が鍵の依代(よりしろ)であるかぎり
二千年前の奇跡は起きぬ
the miracle of two millennia ago will not occur.
Huh? What do you mean?
はあ？　どういうことだ？
Zeus and Satan presently exist in key form;
（ドラゴン）
“神魔(しんま)の鍵”と化した
ゼウスとサタンは
only by the blood of a human vessel can they now be manifest.
依代となる人間の血によってのみ
顕現することができる
But the girl cannot accomplish this role,
じゃが 神と魔 双方の血しか持たぬ
あの娘には
for she only possesses the blood of a god and the blood of a demon.
その役目を果たすことはできぬ道理
つまり アーミラのせいで
You're saying there's no way to keep
Bahamut sealed away because of Amira?
バハムートを封印する方法が
ないってことか？
Yes.
（ドラゴン）
そうだ
Should the key and Bahamut come together, they will be permanently bound.
そして ひとたび 鍵がバハムートと
ひとつになることあらば
それまでだ
再び切り離すことはかなわん
They can never be separated again.
This is the one absolutely immutable truth.
これだけは決して揺るがぬ理(ことわり)ぞ
なんで んなことを 俺に？
Why are you telling me this?
You intend to change fate, do you not?
（ドラゴン）
運命を変えるのであろう？
Then know this:
ならば 覚えておけ
if you wish to stop Bahamut's revival, take the key girl...
バハムートの復活を止めたくば
鍵の娘を…
Wait for me, mother!
（アーミラ）
お母さん 待っててね～！
Mother!
お母さ～ん！
and kill her.
（ドラゴン）
殺すのだ
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
I'm Lucifer.
（ルシフェル）ルシフェルです
（アザゼル）アザゼルです
I'm Azazel.
We're the Fallen Angel Brothers.
（２人）
堕天使(だてんし)ブラザーズです
（ルシフェル）
て… お前 私の部下だろ？
Hold on. You're my crony.
（アザゼル）
その白い羽 お美しい
Your white feathers are nice.
Yours are very nice, too.
（ルシフェル）
お前のも なかなかだぞ
（２人）
「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"Helheim, Land of Lies."
Helheim(ヘルヘイム), Land(ランド) of(オブ) Lies(ライズ)
Illustration:
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week.